quantamagazine.org 2019-12-26

# Quanta Magazine

_Updated: January 9, 2019_ This Privacy Policy describes the privacy practices of the Simons Foundation in connection with our online publications. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, disclose and otherwise process personal information, and explains the rights and choices available to individuals with respect to their information. This Privacy Policy applies to our websites that post a link to this Privacy Policy. For information about the Simons Foundation’s privacy practices in other contexts, or for individuals located in the European Union, please see our [Institutional Privacy Policy](https://www.simonsfoundation.org/sf-privacy-policy/). 

## Personal Information We Collect

### Information you give us

We collect personal information about individuals who interact with the Simons Foundation, including by using our website and subscribing to our publications. The types of personal information we collect include: 

  * **Contact information** , such as your name, email address and social media handles
  * **Feedback and correspondence** , such as information you provide when emailing us or posting public comments
  * **Usage information** , such as information about how you use our websites and interact with us, and information you provide when you use any interactive features of the websites
  * **Subscription information** , such your preferences for receiving communications about our activities, events, and publications, and details about how you engage with our communications

### Information automatically collected

When you access our websites, we, our service providers and partners may automatically log information about you, your computer or mobile device, and your activity on our websites. The information that may be collected automatically includes your device’s operating system type and version number, manufacturer and model, device identifier, browser type, screen resolution, IP address, the website you visited before browsing to our websites, general location information such as city, state or geographic area, and information about your use of and actions on our websites, such as pages you viewed, how long you spent on a page, navigation paths between pages, information about your activity on a page, access times and length of access. This information is collected using cookies, pixel tags and similar technologies. Pixel tags (which are also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) are used on our websites and HTML-formatted emails to track the actions of users on our websites. Unlike cookies, which are stored on the hard drive of your computer or mobile device by a website, pixel tags are embedded invisibly on webpages or within HTML-formatted emails. Pixel tags measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about usage of our websites or engagement with email notices so that we can manage our content more effectively. Please refer to our [Cookies Policy](https://www.simonsfoundation.org/cookies-policy/). for more details about our use of cookies. 

## How We Use Your Personal Information

### To provide our services

We use your personal information to provide our services in the following ways: 

  * to operate, maintain, administer and improve our websites
  * to publish our newsletters, magazines and other communications
  * to manage and communicate with you regarding your account with us, if you have one
  * to better understand your needs and interests and to personalize your experience with the websites
  * to provide support and maintenance for the websites
  * to respond to your requests, questions and feedback

### To communicate with you

If you request information from us (such as signing up for our newsletter or publications) or register on our websites, we may send you Simons Foundation–related communications. You will have the ability to opt out of such communications. 

### To comply with law

We use your personal information as we believe necessary or appropriate to comply with applicable laws, lawful requests and legal processes. 

### With your consent

We will request your consent to use your personal information where required by law, such as where we use certain cookies or similar technologies or would like to send you certain marketing messages. You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time in the manner that was indicated when we requested the consent or at any time by [contacting us](mailto:privacy@simonsfoundation.org). If you have consented to receive marketing communications from our third-party partners, you may withdraw your consent by contacting those partners directly. 

### To create anonymous data for analytics

We may create anonymous data from your personal information and other individuals whose personal information we collect. We make personal information into anonymous data by excluding information that makes the data personally identifiable to you, and use that anonymous data for business purposes. 

### For compliance, fraud prevention and safety

We use your personal information as we believe necessary or appropriate to (a) enforce the terms and conditions that govern the service; (b) protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of you or others; and (c) protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical or illegal activity. 

### As stated in a supplemental privacy notice

In some circumstances, we may provide a supplemental privacy notice that explains how we use personal information in a specific context. 

### Affiliates

We may disclose your personal information to our subsidiaries and corporate affiliates for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

### Service providers and professional advisors

We may employ third-party companies and individuals to administer and provide our services on our behalf (such as hosting, email delivery, database management services). These third parties may use your information only as directed by the Simons Foundation and in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy, and are prohibited from using or disclosing your information for any other purpose. 

### Partners

We may sometimes share your personal information with partners or enable partners to collect information via our websites. For example, some of our websites use Disqus, a third-party service that enables our visitors to post comments on our website. You may view the Disqus Privacy Policy [here](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy) and control Disqus targeting and personalization [here](https://disqus.com/data-sharing-settings/). 

### Professional advisers

We may disclose your personal information to professional advisers, such as lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers, where necessary in the course of the professional services that they render to us. 

### Compliance with laws and law enforcement; protection and safety

We may disclose information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as required by law, and disclose and use such information as we believe necessary or appropriate to (a) comply with applicable laws and lawful requests and legal processes, such as to respond to subpoenas; (b) enforce the terms and conditions that govern our websites; (c) protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of you or others; and (d) protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical or illegal activity. 

### **Corporate transfers**

In the event that the Simons Foundation sells or transfers some or all of its businesses, operations or assets (or enters into negotiations for such a sale or transfer), such as via a merger, consolidation, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, or bankruptcy proceeding, your personal information typically will be included as part of that sale or transfer. We will make reasonable efforts to require the recipient to honor this Privacy Policy. 

## Your Choices

### Access, update, correct or delete your information

An individual who has registered for an account with us may review, update, correct or delete the personal information in their account profile by logging into their account. 

### Marketing communications

You may opt out of marketing-related emails by following the instructions contained at the bottom of our emails, or by contacting us at privacy@simonsfoundation.org. You may continue to receive service-related and other nonmarketing emails. 

### Online behavioral advertising

Some of the partners that collect information about users’ activities on our websites may be members of organizations or programs that provide choices to individuals regarding targeted advertising. Users may opt out of receiving targeted advertising on websites through members of the Network Advertising Initiative by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) or the Digital Advertising Alliance by clicking [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). European users may opt out of receiving targeted advertising on websites through members of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance by clicking [here](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/), selecting the user’s country, and then clicking “Choices” (or similarly titled link). If you choose to opt out of targeted advertisements, you will still see advertisements online, but they may not be relevant to you. Even if you do choose to opt out, not all companies that serve online behavioral advertising are included in this list, and so you may still receive some cookies and tailored advertisements from companies that are not listed. 

### “Do Not Track” signals

Some Internet browsers may be configured to send “Do Not Track” signals to the online services that you visit. We currently do not honor “Do Not Track” signals. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/). 

### Choosing not to share your personal information

You may choose not to provide personal information to us. However, we may not be able to provide services to you if we are required to collect your personal information or if we need your personal information in order to provide the services. We will tell you what information you must provide to receive our services by designating it as required or through other appropriate means. 

## Security

We take a number of organizational, technical and physical measures designed to protect the personal information we collect, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no security safeguards are 100% secure, and we cannot guarantee the security of your information. 

### **Children**

Our websites are not intended for children under 16. If you become aware that a child has provided us with information without parental or guardian consent, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@simonsfoundation.org). We will delete such information from our files as soon as reasonably practicable. 

## International Transfer

Simons Foundation is headquartered in the United States and may have service providers in other countries. Your personal information may be transferred to the United States or other locations outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. European Union users should read the important information provided in our [Institutional Privacy Policy](https://www.simonsfoundation.org/sf-privacy-policy/) about transfer of personal information outside of the European Economic Area. 

## Other Sites and Services

Our websites may contain links to other websites and services. These links are not an endorsement, authorization or representation that we are affiliated with that third party. We do not exercise control over third-party websites or services, and are not responsible for their actions. Other websites and services may follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of the other websites you visit and services you use. 

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by updating the date of this Privacy Policy and posting it on our websites. We may (and, where required by law, will) also provide notification of changes in another way that we believe is reasonably likely to reach you, such as via e-mail (if you have an account where we have your contact information) or another manner through the Service (which may include posting an announcement on our websites). Any modifications to this Privacy Policy will be effective upon our posting of the new terms and/or upon implementation of the new changes on the Service (or as otherwise indicated at the time of posting). In all cases, your continued use of our websites after the posting of any modified Privacy Policy indicates your acceptance of the terms of the modified Privacy Policy. 

If you have any questions or concerns at all about our Privacy Policy, please feel free to email us at privacy@simonsfoundation.org. or write to us at: Simons Foundation Attn: Legal – Privacy 160 Fifth Ave., 7th Floor New York, NY 10010 Additional information and policies can be found in our [Terms & Conditions](https://www.quantamagazine.org/terms-conditions/) document.
